<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<article version="5.0" xml:lang="en"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <title></title>

  <section>
    <title>TODO list for MynPad</title>

    <section>
      <title>Next steps</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>External URL handling</para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>when marking a text fragment as URL, then, if the text fragment starts with http:// or https://, then use the fragment as default for the HREF</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Also open the url editor immediately when marking a fragment as URL</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Search functionality</para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Need to find a concept for navigation - currently an issue <emphasis role="highlight">when switching between notepads and then selecting the search result from an earlier search!</emphasis></para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para><emphasis role="highlight">Navigation to title page fails</emphasis> (since its page id is "None")</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Add page name to article's &lt;title&gt; tag</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Bugs</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>List related</para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>if a nested list is indented more than once from its parent list, invalid docbook XML is created - in docbook, each itemizedlist MUST contain a listitem! Possible solution to generate valid docbook is to either prevent the user from creating lists with missing intermediate levels (might be too complex) or to use a special attribute to determine the actual nesting level (like role="level:2"). A third alternative would be to keep creating invalid docbook in this particular case - not a preferred approach, though...</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>List format not reflected in Block style toolbar</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Unindent List must add item to right list (important for numbered / ordered lists)</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Editing a list of keyword links is a mess - the format of the previous list item is taken, thus effectively inserting a keyword link - even if resetting the format, once the list item content is deleted to its beginning (with backspace), when entering new characters, again the format from the previous item is used.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Update Browser when new page is created - done, but item is not yet created at the right location!</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>UNDO/REDO state not reset when saving a page</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Make XMLExporter more robust - must not destroy existing page!!!</emphasis></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Important topics</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>How to delete / rename pages?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Copy&amp;Paste should support format - currently only plain text is copied into the clipboard</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>support of numbered (ordered) lists</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Return key inside block (e.g. inside code block)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Tab key - inside lists, should increase indent</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Back and Forward navigation</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Rework page creation - especially on Dropbox, requires too many roundtrips</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Maintain creation date and last update date for each page</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Clean up unused image files - probably simply delete unused files when saving the page</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Support of tables. Currently an issue since the <code>QTextTableCell</code> is missing the python methods for <code>begin()</code> and <code>end()</code>, so that it is not possible to traverse the table cells contents.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Enhancements</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Show current cursor position (line/column)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Ideas</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Style Editor</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>MathML integration</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Thumbnail view of all Images contained in a Notepad</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Version Control of pages</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Syntax highlighting inside code blocks</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Spell checker</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Inline resizing of images through some kind of handles - this will most likely require the implementation of a custom text object, see <link xlink:href="http://doc.qt.io/qt-5/qtsvg-richtext-textobject-example.html">http://doc.qt.io/qt-5/qtsvg-richtext-textobject-example.html</link></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
</article>
